[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 17]
[This story is purely fictional]
Come, my friend.
Have some water.
You said you saw the Japanese
with the Zhainiangniang,
and they could communicate with it?
The mountain deity is a monster.
It was tamed by the Japanese.
Tiezui.
Master Zhang.
Laogou's whistle?
The Japanese kidnapped him
to tame Zhainiangniang.
The underground river cannot access the depths of the Xumi Realm.
It's even riddled with miasma.
The Japanese can only go there with the help of Zhainiangniang.
According to the murals,
there are two ways to enter the Xumi Realm.
One.
Zhainiangniang can carry you inside.
But it has now been killed by you.
And two.
Take the Lifeswapping Herb.
But that's poisonous.
You need the golden pot to cure the poison.
Here's the problem.
We don't have the golden pot.
Oh, Laogou.
If you could tame Zhainiangniang,
why didn't you ask it
to kill all the Japanese?
Eighth Master.
Zhainiangniang is not a dog.
It's not that docile.
I bet
Eighth Master is in grave danger as well.
You don't know Laogou well enough.
He's as slippery as an eel.
He'll keep himself safe.
Master Zhang.
What do we do next?
Let's investigate the edges of the Xumi Realm
and find a way in.
My friend,
let's continue.
You mentioned
Japanese soldiers who came back from the dead.
What did you mean by that?
The mountain deity punished us.
We were all killed.
You mean
the Japanese went in the direction of the flare?
That must be the hideout of Yoshiyuki Hatoyama and his unit.
You said
they came back from the dead,
and they killed all of you?
If they were this powerful,
they should come out and kill us now.
Why are they hiding instead?
Could it be that Hatoyama is testing another spell?
The golden pot.
The golden pot you saw on the mural
must be the pot Hatoyama used to place his spell.
When I was interrogating Ding Qiansui,
he kept saying
that Hatoyama had mastered everything
in the Otherworld Tower.
The golden pot
must contain the secret of the Otherworld Tower.
Fate is cruel.
If I had known this would happen,
I would have
told you everything
about Wu Laogou.
Master Zhang.
Master Zhang, please bury us.
We have carried out the purpose of our lives.
You have achieved far more than what ordinary folk ever will.
But we misplaced our belief,
and so, we ended up hurting people.
To some, fire
can bring light.
But it can also burn.
All of you are formidable warriors.
Thank you.
All of you are heroes as well.
What else can I do for you?
I want to listen to the story of Wu Laogou.
Then, I'll tell Ma Jinbao his story in the afterlife.
Back then, there was a famine in Changsha. People were displaced.
They banded together to steal food.
Fifth Master was among them.
Mister.
Brother, I know him.
He's a hooligan in the city
who takes advantage of people like us.
Sir, spare me some food, please.
Miscreant! How dare you steal our belongings?
Kill him.
Brother.
Stop. He'll die.
Move aside.
Let's go.
Little boy.
Who abandoned you here?
I'll raise you from now on.
You shall be Xiaozhu.
The name sounds tough.
I hope you'll be
a tough guy like me.
Who's there?
What are you doing here?
You want more beating?
You can have this.
I don't like to be indebted to anyone.
If you don't save yourself,
no one else will save you.
The immortals from high above do not notice common folks like us.
Eat it.
Work for me from now on.
Have you watched The Heavenly Peace Celebration?
I will establish
our very own safe haven in Changsha.
So?
Do you like your new outfit?
Listen.
From now on, you're my buddy.
We just need a fortress now.
Should we
open a dog farm?
We dug out money to buy new clothes.
If you can get us a plot of land,
I'll follow you
and be loyal to you.
Let me show you.
I taught you how to sit down just now.
Did you forget already?
Again.
Sit.
Good boy.
- You're back. - I'm hungry.
I'm back.
- Go and eat. - Okay.
Laogou.
Your food is here.
We bought this dog farm
a long time ago.
How come we still don't have any customers?
Running a business sure is tough.
Perhaps
no one knows
what we're selling?
Are you blind?
Isn't it obvious?
We sell guard dogs.
You picked these dogs up from the street.
They have not been trained.
Right.
Xiaozhu. Eat now.
Once you're full, I need you to do a somersault.
Do it 10,000 times per day.
10,000 times.
Don't laugh.
You will learn how to throw a punch.
Do it 10,000 times per day.
10,000 times?
You're supposed to tame the dogs, not me.
Will 1,000 times do?
You need to be strong.
Like me.
That way, no one will bully us.
Listen.
I have foreseen
that our dog farm will be a huge deal.
It will be successful soon.
When we have more dogs and customers,
our buns will have meat in them.
As much meat as you want.
Okay. I believe whatever you say.
[Tongxing Boutique]
Come back again.
Careful, mister.
You are what you wear.
Getting an expensive outfit sure changes everything.
Hi, sir.
Sir.
Sir, help us.
Spare us some food.
- My child hasn't eaten for three days. - Go away.
Please spare us some food.
Please.
The world is unfair.
The government doesn't care about us.
- The gods don't care about us either. - Sir.
Sir, please help us.
Please.
Sir, spare us some food.
Please, sir.
Please. Some food, please.
Sir.
Make some noodles for them.
I'll pay for it.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
- Thank you, sir. - Come with me after you eat.
I'll find you a home.
Thank you, sir.
Useless Mystic Nine.
Useless gods.
I'll save
those you don't save.
[Former Fifth Master of the Mystic Nine]
Hurry up.
Trying to escape?
Why are you hiding here?
Escape again, I dare you.
No. No.
- Never escape again. - Work harder!
Escape again, I dare you.
Hurry up.
I'll whip you to death.
Never escape again.
Run!
You stupid dog breeders.
Do you even know who I am?
Fifth Master of the Mystic Nine.
Release them and hand over their indentures.
Then, I'll spare your life.
Who do you think you are?
Trying to cross the Mystic Nine?
The Mystic Nine has been abusing their power.
Is Master Zhang not going to do something about it?
Master,
their leader stays in their lofty palace.
I heard the Mystic Nine has thousands of members.
Zhang Qishan probably doesn't know about a trivial matter like this.
Let's teach this guy a lesson on his behalf.
Touch me if you dare.
Master.
The Mystic Nine also has a rule.
Whoever defeats the leader of a clan
gets to take over his position in the Mystic Nine.
You think you can take over my position?
Killing you
will do justice to everyone else
and earn me a solid reputation.
What's the saying again?
One chicken, two drumsticks?
Two stones, one bird.
You have a death wish!
[Fifth]
[Changsha Mystic Nine, Token]
Master.
You are now the Fifth Master of the Mystic Nine.
Congratulations, Master.
Well done, Master.
- Fifth Master! - Thank you for saving us.
Thank you, Fifth Master.
Thank you for saving us, Fifth Master.
[Shared Legacy of the Mystic Nine]
I am Wu Laogou.
Owner of a dog farm.
[Fifth]
I am now the Fifth Master.
We have a new Fifth Master.
Great. Master Zhang isn't here yet.
So you can enjoy your seat for a while.
Ever since,
Wu Laogou ceased being Wu Laogou,
and has become the Fifth Master of the Mystic Nine.
His wish of seeing Master Zhang
also came true.
Master Zhang.
Look.
The baby sleeps so soundly
in this god-forsaken place.
Isn't that odd?
It feels like
this baby has been actively guiding us on this trip.
It's almost as if someone is controlling the baby.
What do you think?
Don't be mad if I tell you my opinion.
Just say it.
This baby can sense the monster.
It can also make expressions that only an adult can make.
Perhaps he's not a baby at all?
What do you mean?
He's an adult.
Impossible.
Perhaps
this baby has a special power.
For instance, he can sense invisible monsters,
and we can't.
Master Zhang...
You know I don't believe in magic.
Don't be superstitious.
[Shushen Hall]
Xiaozhu?
What are you doing here?
Laogou?
Girls!
Miss Huo?
Gather everyone. We're going to Xiangxi to save someone.
Save someone?
Where in Xiangxi is he?
I'm not sure yet.
Probably somewhere with a river.
But there are many rivers in Xiangxi.
We'll find out when we're there.
But our clan barely settled down.
There are many things to manage,
and we lack manpower.
Perhaps I'll ask for help from the Mystic Nine?
Not many people trust me.
I'll be found out
regardless of who I send as my messenger.
If the Japanese find out,
things can be dire.
What should we do, then?
There's someone else I trust
in the Mystic Nine.
It seems like
I have to visit Lunar Hotel
in Beiping.
Tiezui.
What's on your mind?
I'm worried about Stinky Yu.
He's seriously injured.
When is he going to make a full recovery?
Besides,
there are many wild animals in the mountains.
Xiaojin is taking care of him alone.
Will they be in danger?
He's from my clan.
Our blood is different.
Wounds will heal faster.
Don't worry about him.
Oh. How could I forget about that?
You're right.
This isn't what you wanted to tell me, is it?
You know me so well, Master Zhang.
You see,
what do you think would happen
if Hatoyama took the risk to come back up here
from the Otherworld Tower?
Even with Ding Qiansui protecting him,
will he be able to leave Changsha City?
He won't be able to leave the city.
When the Mystic Nine caught the spies,
we sealed all the secret passages leading to the outside of the city.
So, he can only take the underground river. Right?
Carry on.
Master Zhang, perhaps
Hatoyama took the underground river
to avoid the mountain deity,
also known as Zhainiangniang.
If they came up to the ground,
they wouldn't be able to go past Mount Heimen.
Avoid?
Do you think the Japanese would do that?
They strap grenades
on someone and toss him
to the mountain deity.
Right.
I believe they didn't come up to the ground
not because it would be a difficult journey,
but because they have no idea
where they are heading.
Only by following the underground river
can they find the precise location.
That makes sense, Master Zhang.
Master Zhang.
Hatoyama should be inside the mountain.
Many unknown mountains
lie behind Mount Heimen.
So many mountains.
Where should we start?
We look for smoke during the day
and wind during the night.
[Several Days Later]
Master.
No traces of the Japanese here.
And no entry found either.
Master, I found nothing there either.
This miasma forest
is bigger than we expected.
We're just scratching the surface.
Should we continue?
Continue.
Yes.
If Hatoyama has been here,
he'll surely leave something behind.
[Beiping]
[Station Entrance]
[Lunar Hotel]
Thanks.
A rare guest.
Ms. Yin.
Miss Huo, you came all the way to Beiping.
Did something bad happen in Changsha?
The Mystic Nine
has undergone some changes
due to Unit 401.
I'm sure you're already aware of it.
My husband did tell me about it.
Laogou was kidnapped by the Japanese,
and they went to Xiangxi to pursue him.
I
obtained important information in Changsha.
However,
I do not have the means to deliver it to Master Zhang.
I came seeking your help.
I wonder if you can reach Master Zhang
and tell him to return to Changsha at once.
What makes you think I can contact him?
You're important to him.
No matter where he is,
he'll find a way to contact you.
Besides,
Master Zhang can ignore everyone's message,
but never yours.
Miss Huo,
can I ask you something?
What is
Wu Laogou to you?
We're lovers.
I didn't expect honesty from you.
I need a favor from you.
Naturally, I have to be open and honest.
You claimed to be open and honest.
But here you are, asking me to tell my husband
to give up on Wu Laogou and return to Changsha.
You must have news of Laogou.
Why can't you tell him right away?
Because I have my reason, which I can't tell anyone.
But if I can come here to seek your help,
it means I have a plan.
I will not put you
or Master Zhang in danger.
Here's the catch.
I will only help you find my husband.
Thank you.
[Trove of all Treasures]
I have found a way to escape.
It is ingenious and dangerous at the same time.
If you're reading this,
please follow my instructions
correctly.
Otherwise, I'll die.
It's okay if you don't want to take the risk.
Walk your own path.
Miss Huo.
Are you lost?
I am a friend of your master,
Yin Xinyue.
I just had a meal with her.
I thought I could walk around a bit
to sober up.
You see, Miss Huo,
this is the internal hall of Lunar Hotel.
Many things here are confidential.
No one can enter.
Let me send you off.
I heard the chief auctioneer of the internal hall
oversees every auction in Lunar Hotel.
He's good with math
and possesses sharp business acumen.
Can you bring me to him?
I would like to pitch a sale to your chief auctioneer.
A reliable source of mine
told me that highly valuable ascended mummies
will soon appear in Xiangxi.
However, the mummies are located in a hidden, complex area.
One can only find them if a huge investor like Lunar Hotel
puts in the money and manpower.
The mummies are of high quality.
If you find them,
you'll earn a fortune.
I wonder if you've heard the rumor
that the Huo Clan is laden with debts.
The rumor is true.
I came here today
to save my clan.
[10,000 yuan, Check]
These two checks prove my sincerity.
You can keep it as collateral.
If you find the ascended mummies
using my information,
you will have to pay me 10 times the amount.
If you do not find the mummies,
you can keep the checks.
Miss Huo, you should leave.
I'm new here.
I do not know the rules in place.
Forgive the insolence
I displayed just now.
Farewell.
Wait.
[Chief Auctioneer]
Miss Huo, you came with such sincerity.
We shouldn't disappoint you.
[Two Weeks Later]
You recovered so quickly.
As expected of the Zhang Clan.
Take this.
Thanks.
Well done.
There, there.
Master Zhang.
It's been two weeks.
This baby will be old enough
to find a wife if we still don't find the Japanese.
He's right.
We know they are here,
but we just can't find them.
They don't start a fire during the day,
and they don't put on lights either at night.
How disciplined.
If this carries on,
we won't be able to find them.
Then let's go down and find them.
No. Our number is too small.
If we assign one person to each mountain,
it'll take at least three years to search this place.
You know what, Master Zhang?
Carry the baby for me.
We'll lay a trap.
We start a fire at night
to invite them to ambush us.
Hatoyama is a seasoned strategist.
Do you think he'll fall for it?
Right.
What should we do now then?
If this persists,
Hatoyama's plan will come to fruition.
Ask some to stay here.
The rest will return to Changsha
to dig the Otherworld Tower.
We'll take the underground river?
Despite Zhang Qishan's brilliant mind,
the lead came to a dead end once again at Xiangxi.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama's slyness
left the Mystic Nine stumped.
Unbeknownst to them,
another plan
is carefully unfolding under Wu Laogou's
machinations.
Xiangxi has a lot of rivers.
Upon receiving the information from Huo Xiangu,
Lunar Hotel's informants in Xiangxi
bought 82 Stockade
to investigate every river.
Eventually, they found their treasure
on a small branch of the Xijiang River.
Bring it up.
Open it.
An ascended mummy!
Bring it back.
Yes.
Master.
An urgent telegram from Beiping.
I've been having nightmares.
I keep dreaming about a capsizing boat. It scares me.
I want the osmanthus pastry in Changsha.
Buy some for me.
Master Zhang,
did something happen to your wife?
She's fine.
It's a secret code.
What does it mean then?
She must have missed you so much.
She said that something huge had happened,
and that there was no point in staying here.
She told me to head back to Changsha
as the lead would come to me instead.
How did she find out about all this?
She wouldn't have used this method to contact me
unless there was a huge discovery.
It might be related to Laogou.
Perhaps she used the secret code because the Ministry of War
was monitoring closely.
Let's do as she says and return now.
You don't say.
Return to Changsha.
[Lunar Hotel]
Seal both chests tight.
Do not let air in.
Otherwise, the things inside will decay very quickly.
Send me a telegram to tell me you're safe.
Otherwise,
I'll cheat on you.
Lunar Hotel has become
a place of strife and competition.
Huo Xiangu holds the information. See her immediately.
Xiaojin.
Send a telegram. 8273. To Beiping.
I am home safely.
Do not miss me too much.
Things are still convoluted and dangerous.
I will let you know if there's any update.
Yes.
Is she here?
She has been waiting for you in the back hall. She also said
that you
should see her when you arrive.
Master Zhang, I'm surprised
that you actually rushed back upon receiving the telegram.
I trust
you never joke around when it comes to Laogou.
Did you find him?
Too few leads.
Same here.
These are new items coming next month in Lunar Hotel's auction.
In his message, Laogou mentioned
these two chests.
Did he say where he was
and how to save him?
No, he did not.
Laogou said those two chests
were the key to finding him.
I made it so that the Lunar Hotel secured the chests.
But I can't do much about the rest.
Master Zhang, I hope you can do your best
to win the bid for the chests.
That way, the truth
will surface.
The Lunar Hotel is unique in the sense
that it houses every precious item in the world.
No one is guaranteed
to get what they want in the auction.
But you
are the owner's son-in-law.
I'm sure this won't be too difficult
for you.
I'm counting on you, Master Zhang.
Given my relationship with Laogou,
I should come with you.
But my clan has undergone a lot of changes.
I have a lot on my plate.
So, I shall not burden you further.
Do you need help?
Xiangu, you went to Beiping without telling us.
Why can't we maintain open communication with each other?
We are familiar with the Lunar Hotel.
Coincidentally, these antiques
require appraisal from a professional
before we can trust them.
Therefore, I'd like to invite you
to come to the auction with us.
How come
you're so interested in the places I've been?
Your sudden visit to the Lunar Hotel
might be closely connected
to another incident
we encountered.
Spare me the details.
I do not want to know everything.
If it has nothing to do with you,
what's stopping you from joining us?
In Beiping,
Lunar Hotel is not an ordinary auction hall.
What's in it for me
if I come with you?
I promise you
that your ailment
will be cured.
Find Laogou.
I can handle
the rest.
Guards.
Bring Eighth Master over.
[Beiping City's Latest Map]
Master Zhang,
you've been studying it for a while.
Take a break and eat something.
You're so carefree, Eighth Master.
You still have a good appetite.
Fill your stomach first.
There is still hope now.
If we fall here, how are we supposed
to save Laogou?
Auction Item No. 038 and 039
in the Lunar Hotel.
They are
two chests containing ascended mummies.
Tiezui, check
if they came from Xiangxi.
[Artifact Chest]
Yes, they are.
Laogou wrote to Xiangu
telling her that the artifact chests led to him.
Therefore, we must win the bid for the chests.
He wrote to Xiangu?
Right.
Both of them
should share a way of communicating.
Every rich man in this nation
has now gathered in Beiping.
On the eve of battle,
they want to turn liquidity into antiques
before transferring them abroad.
They will achieve this at all costs.
Even if we combine all our assets in the Mystic Nine,
we probably will lose the bid.
Master Zhang,
aren't you the son-in-law of Lunar Hotel?
Lunar Hotel was established 300 years ago.
Their rules have never been broken before.
A son-in-law is replaceable.
Their reputation is the foundation of their success.
Then, we need to prepare enough money.
You still haven't paid me back for the blanket bid I made back then.
Even if we were as rich as before,
we still wouldn't win the bid.
I see, Master Zhang.
Let me buy some joss paper
and burn it for Laogou.
May he rest in peace.
Today will be his death anniversary.
What do you think?
So, instead of bidding for it
in the Lunar Hotel,
we steal it.
Steal it?
The most expensive antiques are,
without exception,
auctioned in the Lunar Hotel.
The influence of the Lunar Hotel runs deep.
Their rules must be respected, whether you're a law-abiding citizen
or a gangster.
In this trip, other than the other buyers,
we must guard against ear slaves
and pole slaves.
Ear slaves have good hearing.
They can pick up any noise within a 100-meter radius.
Anything that happens during the auction
will not escape their ears.
Pole slaves are masters of polearms.
Their polearms contain poisonous needles.
They can kill someone from a great distance.
If a rabble-rouser runs into a pole slave
in the Lunar Hotel,
they will die within five steps.
The latest auction in the Lunar Hotel
has also turned underground.
[Lunar Hotel]
There is a new rule.
Before the hour of Xu, it's the morning session.
After the hour of Xu, it's the evening session.
You need to win the bid for three items in the morning session
to join the evening session.
During the auction,
you can sit individually or in a private cabin.
Those in the private cabin can make a blanket bid.
Those two items that Laogou wants us to bid
will surely appear in the evening session.
Thus, our mission is
firstly,
win the bid
of three items in the morning session
to enter the evening session.
Secondly,
we will secure a private cabin
in the evening session.
[Beiping City's Latest Map]
How can we secure a private cabin, then?
There are so many rich people in Beiping now.
Even if we pool the wealth of the Mystic Nine,
we will probably
be given individual seats.
That's embarrassing, Master Zhang.
It's easy to secure a private cabin.
You just need money.
With enough money,
you can enter a private cabin.
I see.
You want us to raise funds
for you to sit alone in the cabin.
The rest will sit on individual seats.
No.
One private cabin can accommodate two people.
We need two private cabins at least.
One to hype the scene
and draw the attention of the ear slaves.
The other cabin to...
To steal
the chests
and kidnap your father-in-law.
Do whatever we can to get the chests
and restore your bachelor status.
Who is the richest in the Mystic Nine?
Xie Jiu.
Isn't the case he's dealing with now
the consequences of what he did
when he helped you in the Lunar Hotel?
And he shall solve it where it began.
Gather our accounts
and bring
all of your money.
Master Zhang, I have no money.
I was already penniless last time.
Xiangu won't join us
in Beiping.
Just the three of us won't make the cut.
We need
two more people on top of Xie Jiu.
Two more people?
I'll handle Xie Jiu.
Find the rest yourself.
Master Zhang.
This will be challenging.
While the meeting we had last time
seems to suggest that there is unity among us,
but we all know
that we each have a mess to clean up.
Our subordinates have long-standing feuds,
and now you want him to help you?
That's a tall order.
I believe the Mystic Nine
knows what the right thing to do is.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪